Guide to the Duke University Archives Scrapbook collection, 1916-ongoing
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Duke University Archives Scrapbook collection 1916-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. University Archives
9.5 Linear Feet 29 Items
The collection contains scrapbooks for which the creator and/or origin is unknown. They contain clippings, photographs, programs, invitations, and ephemera about Trinity College/Duke University people, athletics and speakers.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The scrapbooks were received by the University Archives over time by various sources, some unknown.
Collection Overview
The collection contains scrapbooks for which the creator and/or origin is unknown. They contain clippings, photographs, programs, invitations, and ephemera about Trinity College/Duke University people, athletics and speakers. Most of the photographs are unidentified regarding people, but many Trinity College/Duke University buildings can be identified. Nine scrapbooks pertain solely to Aycock House from 1945-1964.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Trinity College (Durham, N.C.)--History -- 20th century
Trinity College (Durham, N.C.)--Sports
Trinity College (Durham, N.C.)--Students
Duke University -- History -- 20th century
Duke University -- Sports
Duke University -- Students
Male college students -- North Carolina -- Durham
Women college students -- North Carolina -- Durham
Scrapbooks
Clippings
Postcards
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Scrapbook 1, 1937-1945, Scrapbook 1 contains clippings regarding Duke University, its administrators and benefactors, campus events, commencement programs, and celebration programs for both Duke and the North Carolina College for Negroes (now North Carolina Central University). (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1928-1950, Scrapbook 2 contains clippings regarding Duke University, event flyers including the May Day Pageant, and commencement programs.
  - Scrapbook 3, 1924, Scrapbook 3 contains clippings related to Trinity College (Durham, N.C.) and Duke University
  - Scrapbook 4, circa 1924-1936, Scrapbook 4 contains clippings about the Duke family, University administrators, students and events.
  - Scrapbook 5, circa 1930-1940, Scrapbook 5 contains clippings about University President William P. Few.
  - Scrapbook 6, 1943, Scrapbook 6 contains correspondence, clippings, and black and white photographs regarding the December 2, 1943 visit to Duke University by Viscount Halifax, British Ambassador to the U.S. (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook 7, 1943, Scrapbook 7 contains correspondence, clippings, and black and white photographs regarding the January 14, 1943 visit to Duke University by Wendell Willkie.
  - Scrapbook 8, circa 1927-1945, Scrapbook 8 contains clippings about Duke, the University of North Carolina and North Carolina in general as well as programs for events such as the Carolina Playmakers. (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook 9, circa 1927-1938, Scrapbook 9 contains clippings regarding events, such as the Men's Glee Club appearances, as well as pictures removed from printed material and event programs such as recitals and Duke Chapel events.
  - Scrapbook 10, circa 1927-1935, Scrapbook 10 also contains clippings of lectures, recitals, and event at Duke, including dances, choirs and choruses, and when Giovanni Martinelli of the Metropolitan Opera Company sang in 1935.
  - Scrapbook 11, circa 1928-1942, Scrapbook 11 contains clippings related to Duke University Athletics.
  - Scrapbook 12, circa 1928-1935, Scrapbook 12 contains clippings about recitals and events at Duke University, including fraternity, sorority, and secret society events, Duke Chapel events, and lectures.
  - Scrapbook 13, circa 1928-1943, Scrapbook 13 contains clippings regarding North Carolina in general as well as Duke University. Topics include Duke Engineering, lecturers, and the Centennial Celebration in 1938/39. There are programs, including the "Musical Clubs Fall Tour" for 1928 and the Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra's visit to Duke in 1931. Most of the events took place in Page Auditorium. Some clippings and printed matter pertain to Duke University Hospital.
  - Scrapbooks 14-17, 1945-1950, These scrapbooks pertain to Aycock House, one of the residence halls on what is now East Campus. They include pictures of House Council and advisors as well as clippings regarding residents and sororities/fraternities (social and honorary). Also included are social invitations and wedding invitations as well as publicity materials for events. The pages of Scrapbook 15 are especially fragile and should be handled with care. (Box 4)
  - Scrapbooks 18-20, 1951-1958, These scrapbooks pertain to Aycock House, one of the residence halls on what is now East Campus. They include clippings regarding residents, sororities/fraternities (social and honorary) and events at Duke. Also included are Duke University Church bulletins and wedding invitations. (Box 5)
  - Scrapbooks 21-23, 1936-1939, 1960-1964, Scrapbooks 21-22 pertain to Aycock House, one of the residence halls on what is now East Campus. They include clippings regarding residents, sororities/fraternities (social and honorary) and events at Duke. Also included are wedding invitations. Scrapbook 23 contains newspaper and magazine clippings of college football and baseball players and games during the years 1936-1939. Also included are all-star teams with newspaper portraits of individual players. One page is devoted to the leg injury of star Rip Collins. Many of the clippings relate to Duke players, games and coaches, yet UNC-Chapel Hill, Clemson University, Furman University, the University of South Carolina and the Citadel are also represented. (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook 24, 1919-1925, Scrapbook 24 belonged to Grace Long of Mebane, NC. Included in the scrapbook are a 1919 Cornelian Initiation Banquet program, a 1919 Trinity College commencement invitation, a recital program from Enochville School, a Trinity Lutheran Church bulletin, postage stamps, telegrams, name-cards, Valentines, clippings and other epherma. Grace Long had a connection to the North Carolina College for Women as some of the contents related to it. The black and white photographs are largely of identified and unidentified people and buildings, including Trinity College buildings and buildings at the University of North Carolina. Most of the people are posed for the camera, some or around their cars. There is a picture of a plane from this time period as well. There are a couple of pictures of men in what are likely World War I military uniforms. There is one picture of the Durham Reservoir. Some of the images have become detached from the scrapbook. Note that there is handwriting on some of these pictures. These images have been placed in protective sleeves. Towards the end of the scrapbook is a postcard of the Leo Frank lynching (Georgia, 1915). (Box 7)